All right let's get started.
Thank you for coming especially since this the last session on the last
day you guys might not know me but as far as I'm concerned you're my best friend.
So, my name
is anglos that row plus and big surprise I'm originally from greece.
A move to the uk to study where I got my bachelor's and master's
in software engineering if you're wondering why I wasted my time getting a masters
...engineering is because I really wanted to come to the us one day and work and the really
helps with the process so here I am working in visual studio...
Being the product manager for the program manager for inhibitors.
How many of you out of this room have use
intelligence before or are familiar with it so quite a few people that's great I just
want-to make sure that everybody gets exactly what the expect of the session so,
I want to briefly mention the...this is a debugging feature from one
that's code that means we don't support cplus-plus right now and even though you can download
...of visual studio
twenty fifteen right now and you can play with all of the features including
...so you'll be able to replicate exactly what a...today when we hit
...them intelligence is going to be part of the enterprise
...so bone if you stay until the end of the session
you really hate debugging anything else...coding enterprise you buying that...
Mandatory slide if you guys like what you see you want to singing
again in the future please let-me know...you like that so that they will invite me back advances force myself.
So, this session is going to be about how can
intellectually is health you to be more productive during the daily debugging.
If your writing code you also fixing it up least I have never seen
a job posting that says csharp developer needed to write new code don't worry about fixing
it we have another guy for that.
Right.
So, often...the fix a bug in an application where.
You can work in small increments make a few changes in very quickly...your changes and
that's great because you can very quickly figure out if something goes wrong is probably what adjusting.
But, I find
that's typically the exception to the rule usually something else
is happening usually I'm being asked to fix a bug maybe in a part of the application that I didn't
right because I'm working in a team and one of my colleagues
wrote it so I'm not really sure how that part of the application works.
All I need to fix a bag...takes ten or fifteen minutes to
set up to make...ready to replicate...the stupid thing of stepping over
...into and I break my keyboard on...frustrated.
Or...new team when you project and I don't know the code base
very well and I want to be productivethe one of the want anybody to think I don't...to code that just
don't understand the application yet that's need some time to...
Or you...be my home code but I wrote the long-time ago and...don't know...you guys but whenever
look back...code the wrote the past hosting who wrote that stupid...do that way.
So, again, you might have different thoughts.
Or you might be one of those bags...some users reporting it or you're seeing it
in the test environment but it's really hard replicated on your local machine.
Or you don't know exactly how it happens you click around the latin you do a lot of things and by the end with
...but you don't really know-how you got there.
out of curiosity who here has never had to deal with any of this.
Nobody ok good excellent so at least you can see the value
here now there's one more way that we can helpcan help you be more efficient
...debugging other than just fixing bugs like that you will also
be able to spot unexpected behavior even if you're not looking for
...a bit like magic right now butI'll show you exactly how that works
...and it really helps when you fix about before somebody files?
So, how the system's going to play
out is very quickly I'm going to explain what intelligence can do?
Then we're going to dive into a demo where we're
going to compare what it's like to fix the same bug with intelligence and
without so during this demo I'm actually going to be using intelligence...if you all know how it
...stop and explained every ui element and everything
...clicking on because what I wanted to take away from it is are you convinced
that it's actually saving you time and if we spend fifteen twenty minutes talking to everything,
you know, going to take that away from it so we're going to go rather quickly through that but
...keep take away from that is not exactly how it works but how did
I go about my debugging...briefly
pose and have a little retrospective into the demo and then we're going to take a deeper
...when explained everything...clicking on everything that I'm using all the way elements
...there and I'll be able to take questions ...answer and,...you wondering about?
Finally within a wrap-up where...a...what we talked about plus
...going to give you a little pointers to some other intellectually functionality that I think most
of you will find really interesting but I just don't have time to democratic.
So, what...intelligence do?
Basically what your...
is running without you having to do anything special rather than just...
on internal trace will monitored for what it considers interesting
events so what's what is an interesting event let's take a look at some examples this is not an exhaustive list
is a some examples let's say you just study debugging and you're accessing some files to
read some configuration and then the user clicks on the button.
And, then later on you execute some sequel.
...maybe...exception gets thrown somewhere.
Now for this kind of events in penetrates things that you might be interested in what the state of the application
wars when they were generated so what we'll do is
...will look at the application state when adtext them and
...remember the...and some local information for this event
allowing you later on to go back in time and asked hey what was the
calls that when I read those configuration files even though now you might be all the way down...exception.
So, let's go straight into them.
And, I'm going to help here when I am debugging without
...because I want to the...honest I'm not going to cook for
them to make it look good so you're going to help me debug this application...oppressed are.
And, this is a very simple wpf text editor
...us has the ability to open a text file make some changes save them
...so I'm going to just that when I...open?
I'm going to select the text file the contents really
done matter for this bug so I'm going to school to the bottom.
I'm going to show you the when I make some edits?
And, then I'm about to save them what happens is I lose my current context my...going to move up to
the top so
...escobar so I'm going to click on save now you see that everything has been kind of reset
and with the...so this is the bug on address now what would you guys to first.
...question honestly what...the first.
Yeah, what I heard is we're going to take a look at the event handler for the
save button right I mean that's what I would definitely do so go to the
...the break point other very first-line?
Open my application repeat...testing steps.
Now...I do you can...the code right you make a bigger.
I want to give you a minute just
...this code if anything looks suspicious let-me know if you want to change something.
Because I'll just...to see if anything we...
One seventy two text file content the focus
...suspicious I agree I've been bitten by those things the...
So, I'm just going to...using editing continue anything else.
Okay, cool so I'm just going to quickly stepped...to see if anything goes wrong
...unexpected anything abnormal
...everything looks fine we're getting the bites from the textbooks...them to the
file unseen exceptions all right let's see if committing out that...a five.
Unfortunately...still lost my current position on the master and describers
So, what's next.
The...what about...
...the other positions.
Technical call...when you're at the break point ok
...other suggestions.
Whether this...binding ok so basically at this point we all
very quickly decided let's go take a look at the...of the save button we all kind of thought that's
what the problem is it seems pretty simple we took a look nothing is obvious and
now we're trying to find other ways that we can find interesting places to put a break
...so basically what I'm hearing now is I'm going to explore the code a little bit maybe step into a few
things I'm going to explore basically I'm not really sure what to do next so let me show you how without knowing
anything more about this code we can altogether solve this bug using...
...close.
And, here's a quick that for you guys I'm...get rid of the break point because I don't need it.
And, I want to enable...trace which you can do through tools options but,
in case you...didn't know you can actually search for pretty much everything at the very top will actually
...for-youwhether it's a menu item or options...very quickly go from here to
enable intelligence which is under tools options intelligence
...for application once more.
And, I'm not...to do anything special here I'm just going to repeat the exactly what the before open of the
text file...to the bottom.
Make some edits click save.
And, now I want to inspect I
...ask...hey what have you recorded from the let's take a look about now
intended trace let's look at its data when the...has broken and I don't have a break point
anyway I'm not particularly interested in a specific line of code so I'm going to use the
recall functionality that basically is the equivalent of every thread getting
a break point exactly what it so I'll do that and what resources telling me is that
...with broken in a place where you don't have any of your code so I'm not going to show you
...but I don't care because the reason I use that was to look
...temperatures so I'm going to look at this diagnostics tools window?
This is the list of every event that...says has...
When I read through it I see up here there's a clicked open event that's me clicking the
Button...is a file access and file close.
That makes sense because when you read the file you first open it then you read the contents and then you
closer when I see a clicked save.
Event lets me making the changes including save.
And, then I see a file access
follow close file access and foreclosure length.
And, this is suspicious I don't quite understand why after save the file
I would open savy...opening again enclosure again so at this point
already have a better idea of what...going on in this actually kind of make sense from reopening the file
after save it could explain why everything kind of gets reset and everything moves up
to the top but if we're being honest you have a
good-looking framework and you don't mind scrolling some text files and you don't mind not having this
cool integrative experience you can get similar information from things like look for
...but what you can't get is the very next.
...all wondering right now is...why do we have to pairs
both access and close like...they called twice.
What I can do with intelligence...I couldn't do with
the logging tool is I can just click on this event that looks interesting to me which is the
first file access after click save and then click on activate historical debugging?
Now what happens now is the entire id...historical debugging mode as you can see
...the very top of thing...says historical debugging the text editor
showing the line of code that was executed when that event with generated
...me that I was in the save file.
Button vendor and this is exactly the code that...for before so this looks normal.
Now what I want
to do is take a look at the rest of them this close one is probably going to be the end of the using statement but
what I make sure okay yep the editor has shown that the event was generated by the end of
the using statement now...really want to find out is what is the second file
...all about so...to select that one and activities organ bugging.
Now my text editor has moved into the refile
method...makes no sense I have no idea why we file...called of the
...so what I'm curious now is who cold refile.
Now there's an info...here letting me know the id...historical debugging and the there
are some debugged windows are participating in this experience so if I click on
...stuck.
I see that the cost of windows says also historical
debugging brackets that means that this window is actually showing me the
...actually...at that moment in time.
What I can tell hear from the
...that is that refile is called by open file?
Again, this doesn't help me because I'm not really sure...be calling open file of the save I see that open
file is called from on file chains.
And, that from...school from this anonymous methods.
Now this anonymous method is actually the event hunger of the file system...your.
As it turns out the root cause of the...is not the same functionality
it's actually different piece of functionality that allows users to edit
the same document basically if I have a document open and somebody else
opens the same document and makes changes the application detects that and
...shows me a warning telling me five save right now I'm going to overwrite somebody
else's but it looks like we have a bug and when I save my own changes
I tell myself to reload myself so like any good demo the bug can be
...commenting something?
So, here's where the...was on my unfold sense of an
...I'm just going to continue and
when application continuous...the bottom make my changes...
So, thank you.
Now...fully
appreciate what intelligence has to offer me here think about your typical debugging
routine as soon as you see a bug you first thought is where I'm going to put the
...point that is close enough to the root cause of the bag of what vessel but it
hasn't gone over it and we're going to make our best guess tested by repeating
...testing steps...probably not going to get
...the very first-time around so we're going to step through code maybe get a better idea put another
break point and we're going to keep going through this loop until we get close enough to finally figure out the
changes will make so the idea is that you spend a lot of time trying to find the
bug and that's no valuable what's actually valuable is fixing it so what you want to get
the records as fast as possible.
Now within telly trace when you see a bug your first
...be our...yet let's see what
infiltrate has recorded hopefully it's actually going to...me to the root cause of the...like
...did in this example but even if it doesn't even if the...hiding in between those interesting
events...get a better idea of what's going on and I'm probably going to be able to eliminate some
of my hypothesis some of my possible scenarios and I will probably be able to place the break
...later on...a much better accuracy to get to the records much quicker.
So,...a very quick demonstration now we're going to do the deep dive.
I'm sorry I didn't quite understand the question.
Can I put some code...generation events and let me answer the question
...leather on the short answer is you cannot do it through code but there's other ways you can do and
let me answer the question after we complete this demos...flows...
So, let me close.
So, now we're going to work...different application this is an actual
application it's kind of all school because I got it from called
...I didn't want to cook something up I wanted to actually use a real application so, it's a
...forms application that uses a database to maintain...a
list of social club members basically you can registered members and search for them so I'm going
to just that I'm going to register myself by filling in just a required fields?
That's not my real...by the way.
Suffix now engineer married and let's be
...could lose some weight when I register the application is registering me
...here...decision was successful and the bug...been asked to fix is that the
get all search functionality is behaving kind of erratically I'm
told that sometimes it returns records that nobody ever entered so
...help about?
Cyclic...and I got one record which is the one that I actually inserted
...looks that looks like the right data and have another record...has some fields are empty some have
different values I definitely didn't enter that one so I'm not real sure
what this result is awaits coming from?
Now this point I'm thinking either there's something wrong when I register the member
in the first-time or there's something wrong with the way I'm retrieving the results and I'm
and I'm creating invalid records so the application actually has one more type of
sets functionality has the ability to...occupation and
...others so I think what I want to do is I want to search for this record
that has all the unknowns.
And, I want to see if that actually returns because if it returns and maybe
...real recording database so I clicked serves searching for known and unknown.
And, now I'm really confused because
...back...the first record and I really have no idea what's going on.
...the debug this application...we don't know what the start time maybe output and event
...the get all sorry break point on the event handler of get all maybe
a look at the register I'm really very uncomfortable
placing a break point right now so instead what I'm going to do is I'm going to break all just like before.
And, we're going to talk more about this diagnostics tools window and calories so...
only use this list of events down here and I think that's pretty straightforward every event
that intelligence records in this...
I didn't talk about is what's all of this up here.
So, up here I can see my diagnostic session counting down and because some kind in the breaks
...has...so basically this window records replication
wallets executing but while you're taking...time to debug exposing and...waiting for you to the
...then right below it there is this debugged events timeline
...we call.
This these exactly the same data
...listed here exactly the same events are actually shown in the graphical view
Events over time so you can see how they relate to each other.
Now we're breaking up this one list into three timeline...
The first one is break events so every time you to break point you take a step you're going to
...event here and because I just hit the
brake all button on the ...of the like a
hundred and two seconds into the into my debugging session has created a break event
from for the whole duration next in the next
...output events this is typically anything that would go to the
output window integers records and brings into this view so if you use the output window to look at your
modules loading...exiting these kind of events
are here and finally we have every other event...recorded in the table
...in the final truck now if you look at this is last to tracks.
And, use quinton...really hard
like so hard that you can see a little bit into the future.
You might actually see them being sone truck.
Anyway.
So, I really have no idea what to start so I'm going to
...using timeline to orient myself.
When hover over the very first event but...has collected from the in the
...struck and I see that's the gesture of me clicking the login button
...I'm...to scroll of I'm going to movement mouse over to
the next event and that's the gesture of...the register button
then I can see there's a cluster of events here there's a big space?
And, then there's another event which is...get all now I'm not really sure
what the buggies ways of the beginning or the end so I'm going to get one-step-at-a-time I'm going
to drag left click and...with my mouse to select the time around this
cluster of events that seems to be related with me clicking the register button.
So, I'm going to select them.
And, I'm going to write click and says...selection now this that to things
...first of all zoomed in a little bit so I can see all of those events were cramping a
little bit more spaced out of the same time...did is filter might table
view underneath here...that...so...no longer dealing with every event
...only dealing with the events that happened when I clicked register.
Now just looking at this list of events.
I immediately sports a couple of inches statements...the bottom and they seem to be both
...to the same table so that's not something that I expect.
So, if I click on the very first one I actually get to see the sequel that was executed
by application looks like an
...statement into club members
has a bunch of parameters okay I'm going to...down and look at the second one which
seems very similar this again is also doing and insert into club members.
I see...some differences in the parameters there and I see some now so that's very
suspicious so I'm pretty sure what's happening is when I
...the first-time...actually inserted to records in the database and the search
...the real results.
my next question is why is happening twice so I'm going to click on the very first event the very first
insert statement and...debugging again.
I see that...in the create method seems normal look at the call stack.
I see that the creative fold from register...
Obtained
...normal and registered members called by register underscore click.
...noises without I'm going to move on to the other...statement at the
activate historical debugging on that one and I'm thinking back to the same create method
...let's look at the...for this one this time
creators called again by register member...everything's the same so far but
when I see the register member is called by button register
underscore mouse click so this is a really silly bug of basically have to have been how...for the same
...I didn't I forgot that I already had it so had the twice so the bug is a simple as that.
Any questions so far.
So, the question is whether the events that we're seeing here
...because we're using a dot net and the answer is yes.
So, I definitely have at least one bug
right I can then fix it go back and test of my search again and see if there's another but there.
All right pretty straightforward I'll keep going.
So, what I want to show you next?
...let me...debugging first.
...is how you can solve some common problems using
...you so how we can be helpful doing general
debugging but I want to show you some other things as well some specific scenarios where you when
you see that scenario you mind immediately goes okay I'm going to use intelligence to show this out.
So, I don't know-how many of you do...how many of you here do ace encode
you to use the new wasting functionality to fire off work on a different thread and then
...await to do very quick multi-threaded application but one
of the very most common big issues is that when you're a synchronous code
...exception it actually...visual studio on the
await not with the exception was thrown let me show you what I mean by that...start.
This is a very simple w application has only one-button I'm going to click it.
And, somewhere I'm throwing...exception...visual studio very...breaks execution from
because it's not handled by anyone and tells me that whatever you're doing.
Underneath months something a strong...exception but I don't actually know where
...okay my first instinct is let's look inside here...was going on here.
Ok, well, there's no exception being thrown here...have to keep digging and the more complex your ace
...is...of a
...to find this so what if I told you that if you just
go to intelligence and click on the event that says exception
...activate...it takes exactly the line of code the
threat so there's no guesswork there's no looking for code there's no understanding how things are...
You just go to the list click active-x so debugging either.
Now I said before that you can be more efficient while
you're debugging a bug but you can also be more efficient because you can fix a bug before someone
files now what do they mean by that.
Let's say that I'm working
and application like the one by the show you now which is a very simple client-server application
hp dot net and it's basically a contact manager you can add contacts
...details remove them I'm going to just that.
I'm going to the brand-new context when I click save.
...click remove, remove save.
Remove everything seems to work just fine.
So, let's say that for whatever reason I broke into my editor at some point in
I wasn't looking for...bug...hit a break point or I'm writing some code
immediately what catches my eye on the intelligence timeline is a...thing what is...thing
...highlighted...the time.
The list below
...been filter to the time with whether...happened tells me there's an exception...well I didn't I didn't get any warning
I didn't get a didn't seem to be any problem in the application if I click
...debugging but I actually see is.
When you try to insert to...with the same email address
the intellectually fails but I never got any notification of the
...so when somebody actually runs into this bag
...going to tell me that when I try to enter
to contact with the same email address have a problem we're going to tell me is...sometimes...them save?
And, I'm going to...okay what's your...and other now sometimes we work sometimes it doesn't...just because it's a...
exception and I have no...so when we have this type of problem there's two parts
to the fix the first part is let's make sure the exception is throne for legitimate reasons
like should they really be through an exception in this case maybe yes maybe not maybe I'll fix
that the second part which is a little bit harder is figuring out why was
this woman why didn't they get an error on my ui so if you have to solve this problem right
now what would you do to find where this exception was
...because there's no try cuts here.
Look, at the construct the...like at the throw is going to say.
I'm right there I'm talking about the cuts I'm talking about where was handled.
Thank you...said what about the code events so the answer is I was saying basically to tell
I was trying to get to tell me have to look at the code
...have to see what is calling this methods...any
...cuts above it because if you put a break point at this point you only going to get the
call stack up to now you know,...no way was handled right so if you go to intelligence
mandel you click on the...event click
...the historical debugging and it tells you that all the way up the
...where we do the...catching
exceptions because we think the only reason we will ever failed is because of concurrency but that's not true
so this is how it can quickly get to what my event my exception handling is happening.
Sure, absolutely, yeah.
So, the question was if I have a global exception hundred-and-something the global
...x and that's where all my exceptions are being
...and handled and logged will be able to use this for that and the answer is yes absolutely.
So, the...so the comment was that visual studio actually has a pretty cool
...functionality and also the right now if you go to debug.
The but...settings.
You're going to see a dialogue that we actually only recently revamped and twenty-fifth
thing.
And, it shows you all of the exceptions well it's a list of most of the
most common exception types and where you can do is you can say for a particular exception or even for
all of them I...visual studio to break as soon as it happens don't wait to see if it gets
handle run handled...immediately now that's a great piece
of functionality and it's very useful but it's kind of hard to work with
...different scenarios one is you first have to kind of know that type of
the exception so you have to...argument...exception or something like that and the other problem is even if,
you know, the exception and you set it up if you application is throwing
the type of exception in other places and it's old...you're going to keep eating those break
...I don't care about those I want to get the one that is actually a problem so you might actually get this you keep
many times?
With intelligible happen is you're going to
...all of them and you can just go back and find the most appropriate one.
Now they're moving on.
So, let's talk about the few things that we've covered so far so those of you who have seen intelligence
race and use...before you will have not this by now
that the old ui is all gone used to be a
...list on the right-hand side of solution...the same space
...explorer...was a...with no timeline but now
...been integrated into diagnostics tools diagnostics tools is actually a new window into
...fifteen and is the
house for not session toiletries but also the cpu?
And, the memory tool so-if you guys have a chance later
on you should definitely look for the session that myself and untruthful
gave yesterday that talks about the other tools are part of this window and you...also look out for the
...course but explain how you can use diagnoses tool window keep
...application not just as behaving in terms of correctness but also how
...performing.
Now we looked at how using intended trace
...we accelerate your debugging experience basically you're going to spend less time
looking for the bug you going to actually be able to find the bug quicker.
And, we also that if you're just doing...normal debugging and just keeping an eye out for
what is happening you can actually uncover unexpected behavior in this example it
was...an exception was pretty easy to spot but you can uncover other behavior like, for example,
it may be executing too many...statements when...expected to we maybe accessing to...files.
Now there's a whole bunch of stuff
...can do that I don't have the time to them for you right now.
But, I want to tell you about it so that if it sounds interesting to you can go and look it up we have blog posts and
videos for all of this the first thing is you might be wondering how can I make use of
intelligence if I can have visual studio the machine.
Many times I have issues in production or testing environment that when I try to
...local machine...as can get it to happen.
So, the answer is but there's, there's,
there's a way that you can record your applications execution
using entirely trace even if you don't have visual...the record...machine.
And, it's actually very simple you can just search online for the
intelligently standalone collector is a download from
microsoft-dot-com or you can go to the installation folder visual studio
and you will find a cub file that is the...standalone collective...file.
You extract...zip file without any installation...server so you
admins should be perfectly happy there's no installation you messing around with the service...and then you use our so the
...it a please start monitoring this application pool if it's an
expert on that website or...that monitoring
for execute and monitor this application if it's an extra something like that.
So, then the users can use the
...production intelligence recording all those interesting events and when you have finally
seeing the bug reproduce you can then use partial again to stop collection
...collector is going to save all the data has collected
...file so let me very quickly show you what looks like if I go back to my demo?
because I have left over the debugging...just before what I can do is
I can simulate the collector having done this for me but just going to tools.
Debug...session this is going to save it
...I...file if you notice the extension of the file here.
This is exactly the same file format that my standalone collector would use if I was doing this
...production...going to say this.
...I stole debugging and when the standalone collector...production
has save the file you copied back to develop a machine where you have visual studio and
you just say file open file?
Desktop.
Find the answers...you could open.
What happens is just like with
dump debugging we'll show you a quick summary file?
We give you some very quick and useful summary information what machine was using
...and exceptions being...you can click on any exception or any
of information is useful and start debugging from there.
So, at the back session is going to start and you
...see the familiar you either you were you so before.
Difference now is we don't have a timeline in this scenario so we'll have
...points and...have an out the window so we don't have time languages of the list.
But, from here and then go in activities look at debugging just like I would before.
Now if you think if you think...yourselves well this is really useful when I'm running a whole
bunch of tests will be really helpful if when I run the test.
And, there was an issue with us because it failed and,
I want to...about the developer will be great if I could just give the developer nitrous file
...so if that sounds like an
...you interested in take a look at the integration of
...with microsoft...manager.
Imagine...used...manager to
...your test you go through all your steps the test fails.
When...dvs bug item is created the isis
files diplomatically attached to it and...assigned to the developer that little bit just
...click on the access file and it's the same as opening the...follow the...genetical?
Now...functionality...interesting these integration of
...with the microsoft monitoring agent
so imagine that you have your application running and you want...monitoring you want
to see how it behaving without having specific issues and when something goes wrong?
You get a nitrous file back you can open up in visual studio just like you did before.
If that sounds interesting take a look at that integration or you can come
...talking about the social can talk more about any questions so far yes, please.
So, the question is...ahead.
So,...actually three questions their.
First question is do I need to start...race before
...start my application to make sure...can collect from it what can I start my application and then
later on-going attached to it and the answer is yes you can do both, for example,
if you have an application...running...production you don't have to stop it you
consist firepower and say start more than this application pool application is not going
to stop working across for anybody and the same goes if you're using visual studio you can just a
...process has already been studied.
The second part of the question was is there an issue with the sizing is
...correctly so the second part of the question was if I have a
system based generating a whole bunch of events what am I supposed to do...supposed to just
let it run and fill...the hard disk other any issues or performance issues or other issues with illustrates
...the answer is?
There's ways.
There's ways to configuring...trace to work with the way you
...application works and why can't I give you just a straight answer because it really depends what
you code does right if you're code executes tentacle
...a second...for an hour that's a lot of events comparing to and application
that's us axes file of known then so it really depends on what
...application does especially in comparison to how entirely
...to what competitors...interesting so there's two ways you can
calibrating...to make sure that you get the right experience and it doesn't, you know,
fill out the hard disk or kill the performance the first choice
...you have is if you go to tools?
...thank you.
Tools options intelligence events this is the definite list of everything that
intended...considers interesting and you'll notice that some of them
...checked some of them are partially check...some of
them are completely unchecked so basically we've taken a stab
...the most common stuff that people are interested in but if, you know,...application well,
you know, exactly what you interested in you can customize this any way you want
so if, you know,...application creates a whole bunch...a file
...events but you never really have any issues without you can just unsettled...
And, that means that even...the application...generating a whole ton of them they're not going to get
...now the other way that you can optimize the experience is you
can say how much this space...my isis file take up.
This setting here in visual studio is for when you have five but the standalone
collective has a similar feature where it allows you to say I want to
file to never exceed let's say three hundred megabytes so-if
...these records information that is about to
exceed the limit is going to basically...a rolling buffer...going to go but the beginning and
...writing over it so effectively what you have is the last number of
events that happened so this way you can say don't capture absolutely everything
discover the last big chunk of what has happened and I'm sorry but I forgot the last part
...so you need
...to actually get to the code when you're debugging.
And, you should really always generate bb even with...slowed.
...the greek classification plus american...or working great.
This is only...code for now but if you want to see this
in cplus-plus let us know exactly what you want to see for cplus-plus.
I'm going I'm going to show you a slide how you can let us know what features you like and
...and I just give me a sectors...finally...answer question
...kind of builds earlier to give me one second somebody before us me can I have my
own custom events so one quick way.
To add more state to application
aa have you guys seen the new way to edit...break points.
You can either use these floating toolbar or you can rightly can say
...and conditions so the cool thing is that even though this is functionality
that was there before now it's much easier to discover you can create a break point
...action output something to the output window and
then continues execution so it doesn't actually break you will hit the line of code execute
the map right the methods and keep going.
I can write three types of messages here...rate normal text sorry...didn't do that.
And, if I put the dollar sign down I did an entirely sense
list of my pseudo variables are available so I can say this is my caller.
And, then I can use
...braces to access code...real variables so if I
want to add some state doing calories that is not going to
be captured automatically and create a little trace point I can say hey
by give-me whatever is in construct.
Say...is not-so-great don't get type, for example?
And, it's not contact this contract.
That's if I can get...to...to...tennis...works.
So, now what's going to happen is if I closes and
around this code if it hits through this line of code the
...going to be output into the output window and if you remember what I said before
intelligence records...the output window you're going to get a cute little purple
icon on your timeline basically telling this is a custom thing that you added
I'm collecting for-you and I didn't collective automatically.
Yes, please.
Well,...will this work for windows services the answer is yes.
The short answer the longer actually
...a bit tougher than just clicking so...to me right after...can guide you to a
post explains how to do that but the short answer is yes you can use this on collector for when services.
...was a...didn't have philosopher.
The question is the used to be a limitation on the number of intelligence files.
...that sounds like a bag to me I'm not aware of that limitation I would like to talk
...afterwards if you don't mind to get the details those of a.
Always...holds I...if it...point I'm sorry I didn't even know but...
But, I'm glad you've been using...doesn't intend...get your contact those were the.
Anybody else yes.
Does all of this will work with remote debugged not right now?
So, it's really hard to see the lights
...coming and...performance it so that's a great question does having
...intelligence enabled codes a performance hit the short answer
is yes there is some debugging overhead because what intelligence is doing is it's recording
...application is running so you have to take a little bit of time to do that now
the more elaborate answers will how months so like I said before it really,
really depends on what your application is doing if you application is generating events
...betrays considers interesting all the time you're going
to see a much larger overhead than when it is doing a lot less?
Now as a rule of thumb with
the default settings we think from our testing the overhead it's
almost not receivable it's almost negligible the overhead gets larger
the more working application is doing and the more events that you enable under tools options.
...questions.
Yes, hello.
Can you have a trace...
The answer is not right now but we're working on that.
So, the question was how we made...improvements with instrumentation...how we made
an improvement in the collection the short answer is yes we have made some improvements the
more elaborate answer is in this release we
focus mainly on the experience and integration so we didn't go back and
...existing collection about we actually augmented the collection so as you
saw we collect output events we collect break points so we added collection
...but...haven't contains existing ones.
...questions.
So, the question is there any tracing for windows that can be integrated within
...like dw that's a great question and it has been requested
by quite a few people were looking into it right now but it doesn't do it yet and actually
will be very...to find out exactly how you like that
the work exactly how you would imagine that the work so...have it said right after this.
Okay, all right I don't think this and questions right uyvy let's move on.
So, here's another people would kind of ignore this slide but here's a little sugar...many people.
What...doing that?
Thank you.
here's something that many people know look at the very...appoint...talks about send using the
send...functionality based on the top right corner visual studio if use
the functionality and you send a smile and you put the right kind of keywords in their, for example,
if you say entirely trays did this that comes to me if you say the debugged this
...the debugged pm so every single bit of feedback
you give us either positive or negative gets read not by some random person by the
...so...feedback is invaluable
...know that when you see a bug you will probably reported and get...fixed but
what's actually even more available for us is if we know what you guys enjoy using what
...the ten features you actually enjoy like the three of the time that you like because when the
next visual comes and we have to decide what so we keep what works great when
it's improvement we need the data to make that decision.
The other thing I wanted to know is that we definitely always take a look at
user voice user voices a website where you can go and make a suggestion.
And, people can vote for your position or you can vote for other people
suggestion now you might be wondering whether that's going vote for everything you have limited votes so
you have to actually care about what you're voting for and when the time comes for us to decide
what we work on next we always look at that and if we're between two items?
And, one of them has three thousand volts another...a hundred.
...probably going to do the three thousand one so you feedback is invaluable and if you want
to keep up-to-date with anything that happens within the visual...diagnostic space
we always, always, always blog about whether it's a simple feature improvement or
brian you feature so if you go to our diagnostics login subscribe to that you
will always be up-to-date with everything that comes out of the diagnostics depart.
All right any questions now.
No, one.
So, the question is does this percentage...with application insights because application
insights is a service that you can use that will monitor your application
and then when something goes wrong you can take action the answer is we don't have a very good integration story right now but
we're definitely looking...and if you don't mind talking to me afterwards to kind of help
me understand how you would see that working the great?
I'm not really sure I understood the question.
So, I think the question is can you kind of when intended traces running
...production...you keep the history of the files like this is what happened on monday this will
...used in wednesday the answer is that there's no functionality to let you do that
automatically right now because the only way you can actually generate the
...file is if you stop collection so you start the collection...
collecting and then when you stop you actually get the...now that's an interesting feature requests though so?
No, the entire thing is not in memory.
Correct so the question was while the what the
...running is collecting data is everything be kept in memory and the answer is no it's not
everything's been kept in memory we wouldn't do that because then that would affect the production system in terms of memory consumption?
Absolutely you could scripted but if that's something that you guys think...valuable in useful load
lovett if you come and talk to me and explained to me what kind of scenario you're talking about here why would that functionality be
used for.
...please.
Connects been why...on the other person...here's
another little secret that I hate answering questions var when this
thing going to...tm because the answer I give makes me feel like I'm lying because I say I don't know now
here's, here's the reality the product teams?
Make no decisions when it comes to releases...
So, the reason for that is because microsoft has many products and the kind of
need to coordinate and...need to decide how they're going to sell and...going to sell and how it's going to coordinate with other
releases so it's typically the marketing department makes kind
of decisions so the honest answer is I don't know if you ask any pm
at microsoft they would love to have their featuring community we would love to give it away for free would love for all
...use it because that's our baby?
But, if you've got the user voice and you say give
me intellectually envious pro and five thousand people vote maybe can make happen.
Times how many computers we have time something...when creates going to happen.
So, what kind of application having in mind like...or?
So, if you're in the f five scenario instead of visual studio...you using the
...divider then intelligence
will work for that part it's not going to be able to record anything...cplus-plus unfortunately.
All right.
Well, thank you all very much for your time.
Moi focusing.